James C Florez

Entry Level/ Junior Software Developer

1038 Winter Park Dr St Louis, MO 63026 james.florez2323@gmail.com 636-212-2773

Summary of Experience

I am currently enrolled as a full-time student at Ranken University for Web Application and Software Development. I do this as well as work part-time (approximately 30 hours a week) as a Universal Banker for First Mid Bank and Trust in the city of Clayton, Missouri. I have worked

in face-to-face sales for over 8 months and was able to strongly develop my communication and problem-solving skills when it comes to engaging with customers and fellow employees. I developed these skills further by becoming a bartender and being put into situations where I had to develop a conversation with little to no information, with all different age groups. I have been captain of multiple sports programs and found a lot of success in team building over the past decade, and I believe I would find success in transitioning these skills to the software development world.

Skills and Abilities

- Associates in C# coding.
- Associates in HTML and CSS.
- Experienced SQL Server user.
- Great money management skills and awareness of types of financial plans, accounts, and information
- High proficiency in mathematics and statistics. (Original study before coding).
- Proficient sales skills along with excellent oral communication skills.
- Natural leader tendencies and leads by example.

Education

-Ranken University (2022-Currently Enrolled) Field of Study: Software Development GPA: 3.5

- Educated in C#, Java Script, HTML, and CSS, SQL Server, along with some development in other languages.
- Building software applications from scratch and then transitioning into designing websites and phone applications.
- Using Visual Studio and GitHub to create, store, and reuse software code.

-Meramec Community College (2021-2022) Field of Study: Finance GPA: 2.83

Focused on Accounting Degree courses.

 Developed highly efficient financial skills as well as my knowledge of the industry.

Professional Experience

First Mid Bank and Trust: Personal Banker (August 2022-Present)

I am currently employed at First Mid Bank and Trust as a Universal Banker. I do this along with going to school full time. In this job, I manage all different types of transactions between separate accounts at my institution as well as between account at my bank and other bank branches. I also have to do a lot of account maintenance which, in short, is going through our branch system to find any missing information an any business or consumer account and retrieve the necessary information from the customer.

Wildwood Pub and Grill: Bartender (March 2022-October 2022)

Here, I worked as a bartender at this restaurant. I was able to work on my money handling skills as well as learn how to communicate with all different age groups of people. I was in charge of making sure the entire restaurant's funds, were accurate with what they were supposed to be at, at the end of each shift.

Summerplace Business Solutions: Sales Team Lead (October 2021-May 2022)

This company was a 3 rd party, sales company for AT&T. I started my role as a sales lead and left the company as a Corporate Trainer. My job was to travel to different retail locations such as Costco, Sam's Club, Target and Walmart and set up a booth in the electronics section, where I would try to get retail customers to stop shopping and get them to buy one of our products or services.